OK,
so in this video I'm going to demonstrate
you how to download and test your IO
application engineering exercise.
So what we are about to do,
we are focusing.
In this section in the Moodle,
how to download the software and also how
to test your function with the function
test tool. So I will head now to the.
EASG and for the beginning you should be
familiar with this manual.
Manual about the function test tool which
you are about to use in this exercise.
So check out this manual before you start
your test your application.
Go to the testing and maintenance section
here in the manual and from this manual
check out the first three chapters.
Basically this one, this one, this one.
And this one and also how to enter a new
value with this tool.
So check out this entering a new value
section as well.
Please be be familiar with this manual.
Practice the manual manual usage usage as
well before to execute this exercise.
OK,
so let's head out to the actual
downloading procedure and here we are
having the view of our workspace and as
we were speaking.
We should find our own software here and
you can drag this identifier column.
Just check out your software there.
Mine is here.
I'm usually using this search feature.
I am typing my initials here.
That's ACN dash.
Uh.
Dash IO just like this so I can just
focus on this actual.
Actual like a module I'm I'm handling in
this case.
So when you are downloading your software
like this case in this ACN IO application
engineering if you are having here this
real iOS.
Which means that you are communicating
with real field devices just like this
with this temperature measurement or you
are using the field switch for example,
so you cannot download your software.
In this case, from the workspace,
you need to move it to the repository
workspace.
All all the cases you are handling that
kind of IO functions you need to do this
following procedure.
You need to right click your software and
select move the data storage and select
the repository workspace.
Just like this.
And I will move it over there and then I
will change my workspace to repository
and I can see my software over there.
Now I am able to download my software and
always when you are using that IO
functions like profitables.
Or AC and I/O like we are having here.
You need to select here that it is the
real real selection over here when you
are downloading with this those I/O
modules like in this case.
So now we are ready to download our
software,
but first we need to check our function
and we are doing it here in DNA Explorer.
I'm right clicking my software and
selecting here check function.
And I'm leaving as it is.
I'm doing the IO address to check here.
This is like the most important thing
here at the moment.
I need to check that there is no over
overlapping addresses in this repository
workspace.
When I click OK,
it did the check and the check results
can be seen here in the log menu and
check log menu over here.
If you are having some issues,
those are coming here in the last rows
with your own initials.
And there is something red here in this
menu if there is some issues.
With the download,
if you are having some errors,
you can ask me ask me about those errors.
So let's figure out what is wrong if
there are some errors.
If everything's green here,
you are ready to proceed your download.
Let's check a little bit about the
previous material,
about the hardware section of our Valmet
DNA.
What is happening in this following
section?
So here in this one DNA station slash
node and naming principles documentation
we were talking about that.
Process controllers, process stations,
PCs and also the backup features.
And now when we are downloading some
software,
this backup station is actually handling
the download procedure.
So we are downloading our software first
to the backup station and then the backup
station is handling the application so
that it will end up into the correct
process station.
And also if we are having some like a
user interface in our software, it will.
Our software to all the necessary stages.
You don't need to care about this,
but you just need to understand the
principle what is happening in the
download.
That's why there is some things to
remember when you are doing the download
that the backup station is.
Also involved in this back in this
download procedures.
So if we check this from the attachment
section and the system layout,
let's try to figure out there what is
happening.
When we are doing the download.
So we are actually operating here in this
EASG at the moment and when we are
proceeding to download,
the download would go eventually to the
GB01 process station,
but the backup station over here is
actually responsible of that.
Functionality.
So when we are doing the download,
we are downloading here from the EASG to
the GB 01 backup station and from there
our application is going automatically.
To the GB01 process station,
which is the station there in the DB66
lab here in the campus.
That is what is happening there behind
the scenes,
like under the bonnet automatically.
Let's go there and execute the actual
download.
When I right click my software here in
the repository.
I will go to the Downloads tool menu.
And we are having this kind of dialogue.
You don't need to select anything by this
point. When we are downloading the system,
it is just showing that it is downloading
this kind of modules which we which we
created in the software.
And those are going to the GB 01 package,
which means the process station when I
click OK.
It is very fast operation and my software
there is now that they're downloaded to
the process station.
How can we verify that if you open the
you open your software?
You can now.
Use your knowledge from the function test
tool.
And let's do some like testing functions
here in the software.
I will go here in the file menu and
select the test from here which will open
the function test tool for us.
When I'm doing my testing,
I'm actually always in this kind of
application selecting this insert all
test point to the current page,
which will activate the testing points
for all our connections here in the
software.
As you can see what we can see in our
software,
for example this temperature measurement,
it is reading its value from the
temperature measurement and if you
remember the scaling thing which we were
talking earlier, we can see.
That the temperature scaling is
functioning automatically,
just without any like additional scaling.
We can see the temperature here as a
decrease already in a software.
And here we are having the AM,
the analog measurement block and here we
can see the HH value and H value which
are the alarm limits over here.
Let's take a look how this temperature
measurement thing is functioning.
I have the temperature sensor here which
is labels PT100 just like it is in a
software.
And when I start to heat up this sensor
we can see.
That.
The temperature starts to rise.
We can see that there is some delay,
but now we can see the temperature is
rising and take a look that we are having
this temperature alarm.
22 degrees and when I'm heating this you
can see that HA activated now when I was
heating this sensor.
That means that now our high alarm is
active because the HAHA is active.
And as you can see,
the HH alarm is not active.
I need to leave it a little bit more that
we achieve 20 ticks degrees and then the
HHA became active and what is happening
as well.
You can see the red light is activating.
Wow, what?
What does it mean in our software?
Now our temperature is greater than the
HH limit.
It activated this or function which has
now activated this GX100.
And there you can see the same thing.
There is this GX100 red lamp activated
there in nearby the cabinet.
So this is one like the first thing which
is the successful test here in our
software.
And then we need to do some modification
to the software like this is called the
debugging in the volumet DNA.
We are chasing the values here.
Let's change this higher high limit a
little bit bigger so we can deactivate
this red lab.
I will select here this en tool.
And then I will click this high high
alarm value, this float value.
I will click it and I will put here a new
value for example.
30 degrees for example and I will apply,
you will see that the limit goes off and
also our land turned off there in the
cabinet as well.
What else should we do here?
Let's for example use this.
Software button here.
This is like the button in a screen in
our material.
This is this just like we are using this
just like as an initial value of our
software, but we can activate this.
With this function test tool for the
binary values,
we can use this inversion button which
it's called invert binary values here in
the tool menu. If I select that one,
I can invert binary signals just by
clicking it.
And we are once again having this red
lamp active when I activate this another
button how we how we have call that in
our software and you can invert it back
just like the same way.
And there is also this third option which
is switched in the field box and it is
HS100 to tag name of that one.
And let's see if that is functioning with
the same manner.
The HS100 can be seen here.
When I activate it,
you can see it activates the lamp and
same thing I see there in the software.
Just like that.
And there's also this first button which
will activate the yellow lamp.
Let's try that one with this inversion
tool.
I will click inversion and the GX100 one.
Is activated in a software and also there
in a cabinet.
Just like this,
when you are doing your return,
this is like the functioning software.
All the functionalities has been now been
tested.
So now you can report your thing here in
this like a function test format.
You can have these.
Values modified which we try it here just
like this and use the F function test
tool and modify for example this HH limit
and put the both of these buttons on.
Here in the software and take a
screenshot in this case so that your
software can be seen completely and also
that you have used this function,
this tool to modify the values in the
software.
This would be the scene I would like to
see in in the return.
Just take a screenshot from this part
over here that your whole software can
you see your standard number in a
software and those modified values here
as well.
That's about to return.
And now when we are you have completed
your testing,
you will exit this tool with this exit
button and it will return your to this
function DNA Explorer tool.
OK, this is important thing.
What is about to do what?
What will happen next?
Because we need to we need to delete the
software from the backup station and also
from the process station.
This is very important.
Because this is a name based system,
but we are still using those real IO
channels in a cabinet.
So you really need to do this following
steps.
This is very important because if you are
skipping this phase.
The next next student who is about to do
the test is not able to perform the test,
so you are disturbing other students work
if you are not following these
instructions.
So first you need to delete software from
the process station that is happening
from the same menu.
You right click your software and go to
the download to menu.
But from here we are selecting this
delete feature.
With this option we are actually deleting
the software from backup station and also
from the process station.
So then then there will be no software
related to this like application and what
will happen?
You will see that actually there is both
of those lamps were active and when you
are downloading the software like it was
in this in our application,
let's see what is happening.
Now the software is deleted from the.
Uh.
Process station and backup station and
now actually this is not functioning
anymore.
If we will activate or deactivate the
software,
it is not doing the action in a software.
It would be better like new if I would
turn those off.
Before the.
Actually removing of the software.
It will be more like informative,
but let's just trust that it is not there
in the station anymore.
But the next step you need to perform is
your need to move your software.
Back to our workspace of our group that
this will also reserve the iOS for the
next next student who is about to do the
testing when I have moved moved this into
the our workspace.
It will disappear here from the
repository and it can be seen there in
our workspace.
So this is like the procedure you need to
follow and do it precisely as I did to
avoid any issues with the testing
procedure and.
Basically that's all you need to do,
but I will still demonstrate one more
thing.
Just if we are doing this little bit
differently,
I will move this back to the repository.
You don't need to do this when you are
doing your testing.
This is just for the demonstrating
purposes.
I will download this.
I cannot download it here.
This is I'm trying to download in the
virtual mode here because I am at the
workspace.
You can see the yellow color which
indicates that this is in virtual mode
and it is not downloading the actual I/O
modules.
So I need to move this back to the
repository.
And when I go to the repository,
I will download my software again and
take a look of those lams there in the
camera. I will download my software.
And select the replace and all the values
are going into initial value values and
it is chatting the labs.
Now I will show you probably I will
download.
I will open the software here and see the
same thing what is happening.
Just that you can see.
What I'm about to demonstrate here.
When you are doing your testing,
it is probably better to do it this way.
Now we can see that our software function.
We can test it with our speech,
which the lab is activating.
So we are now sure that our software.
Is running there in the process.
When you are doing your actual deletion,
you want to verify that your software is
not running there in the system.
Leave those lamps off just like this.
Let's do the download now.
When I download and delete this function,
download and select the delete.
Just like this and now when I activate
the switch.
I can verify the lab is not churning on,
so my my software is not there in the
process. That is very easy,
easy way to check that your software is
not there.
Now I will once again move my software to
our workspace.
Just like this and now the testing is
completed and so is this video as well.
Thank you.